WhiteCat is an osu player
and when I say player
I mean that he plays the game
he's one of the greatest player to ever touch Osu
and he built a legacy which will most certainly never be forgotten
holding the number one spot for the longest period in history
redefining what it means to aim
and in the process changing the game forever
his presence at the top almost became symbolic of
of true dominance.
with mrekk recently takes the No.1 spot
we saw an unprecedented celebration
because white cat basically defined an entire era of the game
leaving a level of impact only rivaled by the likes of Cookiezi
this is why I don't think the 10 minute video I made last year
did justice to this truly legendary player
and the ridiculous impact that he's had on Osu!
so without further ado
here's the full story of a truly monolithic player
the history of WhiteCat
this story is going to begin
long before whiteCat became who he is today
and even before he began osu
in a place like many others in early 2014
in 2014
the world is in the midst of one of the biggest phenomena in gaming
and just pop culture in general
the minecraft craze
during this time WhiteCat is one of the people enthralled in this
and like many others
after becoming bored of the single player section of the game
he began playing on some servers
and what really ended up catching his attention
was a server called mcpvp
because unlike a lot of other minecraft servers
which were mainly casually focused
mcpvp was pretty intense
it had the super dedicated audience who would spend
hundreds or even thousands of hours to get as good at minecraft pvp as possible
the server also happened to have a pretty large overlap
with other games of similarly dedicated audiences
one of which was osu
and because of this a couple of the best
and most known osu players actually came from mcpvp
a couple notable ones are (???), btmc and
most importantly for this video whiteCat
who was introduced to osu on the server
but never got around to playing it much
because he was well too busy playing mcpvp
this meant an entire year would pass
after he downloaded the game before he would actually start playing for real
as it's likely that he never really would have started
if not for one massive event
and that was mcpvp's premature demise in May of 2015.
"guys this is the end of mcpvp"
this would cause a mass migration to a couple of games
one of which was obviously osu
and with this mass migration away from mcpvp
whiteCat would officially become an active player
after leaving mcpvp
white cow would come to osu and begin playing mainly for fun
but also often in friendly rival-ships
that kept his motivation for the game high
it's a really normal way to begin your osu career
something which most certainly could not be said
for how he was playing the game
since while mainly just playing for fun
he would improve at a rate that may be truly unmatchable
a historically absurd rise they'd eventually come to bite him
but at the time he only reaped its rewards
going from 100 to 300 pp in three months
and less than a year after that getting his first 400
which is even more impressive when you realize that at this time
400 were still not all that common
what might be even more noble than how quickly he achieved this though
was that he did it all in around 25 000 play counts
which to put in perspective
is faster than lifeline and even mrekk
yeah, to say whiteCat is a fast learner would be an understatement
a more accurate description might be a freak of nature
a prodigy who redefined every single convention
set by players from before
during and even after his time
on top of this technical skill he'd found a talent
for reading EZDT
and his skill had kept becoming more and more impressive
to the point where it was at the upper echelon
of what had been done in the game before
but before this was noticed too much
his skilled aim would be broadcast for everyone to see
with his first ever score post
this was for a number one score
on the at the time qualified quaver
a score should still be top 50 on the map to this day
let me repeat at 13
with less than 40k play count
white cows three missing the long version of quaver
it wasn't normal
and since he wasn't getting any worse
he would get a couple more score posts over the next month
one for his Kuchizuke diamond fc
another for his number five score on high score
and one more for his (???) fc
which also happened to be his first 500.
all of these are extremely popular maps
and he was getting top five or even top one scores
which is why these plays being appreciated for what they were
was quite surprising for someone with
as absurd a profile as whiteCat
the reason for this tameness would become clear a bit later though
for now after approving his aim capabilities
white cat was about to set out on
low AR reading has always been one of whiteCat's strongest skills
and unlike his aim at the time
his easy dt skill was in two words
legitimately unignorable
but this is only half the stone that was about to hit him
because with an extremely low play count
and an extremely high proficiency for reading
he could only be considered one thing
a reading prodigy
this was in almost every way more suspicious
than being an aim prodigy
because for the longest time there's been a pretty popular idea
that there are no reading prodigies
like we just got through the lokI chaos situation
and in that case it was proved entirely right
and in almost every case it has been
which would make the fact that at 40k play count
he would fc don don  with Ez,DT
and then self score posted on reddit
a clear ticking time bomb
and when he posted this a flip basically switched
and everyone was against him
and the thing is you can't even really blame them
no one in their right mind would believe
that after so many examples of people claiming to be easy prodigies
and being out as complete frauds
one who not only improved faster than most of these prodigies
but also self-posted their own score
and so clearly wanted attention
was legit
and this score was torn apart because of this
what is important though is at the time
the evidence against him really did boil down
until he improved too fast
but at the same time the evidence for him
was just as weak
everything would clearly come down to his live plays
the first of which would fittingly be on don don  with Ez,DT
where he would be able to nearly replicate his score with a bad camera angle
and then get a worse score with a better camera angle
the thing that many people were looking for in this live play was time warping
or essentially playing the game at a slower speed
and then speeding up a video after
and in the grand scheme of things
this live play does a pretty good job proving his legitimacy
I don't know if i'd call this a huge feat
because well whiteCat was legit
and so everything about this video being lined up
perfectly is just to be expected
but with the complete lack of inconsistencies in the video
people surely believed him
right yeah no
I think Spazza17's comment under this
sort of says everything
since he replied with sorry but the hand cam
looks really sped up
and before anyone says but there's a clock
just look at this it's pretty easy to fake it
it if you even know the basics about video editing
which he clearly does
wow Spazza of hosting cringe
but in all seriousness this take is
hot garbage
it pretty well shows the amount of ignorance that people
are using to keep themselves convinced that whiteCat wasn't legit
I mean the clock white cat uses analog not digital
which makes it far hard to fake
and on top of this nothing is proved
by what he said
like let's say that clocks are really easy to fake
well, ok, that's a cool fact
but it also says nothing about this live play
and this just about summarizes the comment section
under this live play
in the while there is nothing wrong with it
people wanted much more evidence before
they would let him be legit
and the next live play would be met with pretty
similar response and even less attention
he would then finally use
what should have been a pretty sure-fire way to prove his legitimacy
a hand cam stream
and these streams while not being perfect
were also not that bad
there was definitely a bit of delay between his hand came and monitor but
not much else was wrong with them
so what people do
well they either ignored this part
or made up something like well the hand cam isn't synced so it doesn't prove anything
it's all really witch hunty in hindsight
after this he would continue uploading live plays
in hopes of clearing his name
but as time went on these would just receive
less and less attention
and people almost just seem to be ignoring him
and this likely would have stayed the case
for a very long time if not
for one catastrophic event
when in november of 2016
whiteCat was banned
one thing that really surprised me
was that in the support email he received
they said that he was banned for cheating behavior
this throws an entire another wrench in the situation
but it didn't matter too much
because he did multi-account
and boost other people's accounts
which were both bannable offenses
but everyone obviously believed that he was cheating
because of the reputation he had
one of the most frustrating things about this though
is that white cat told everyone that he was banned from multi-accounting
and because support doesn't say why someone is banned
he had no proof of it
and so obviously everyone thought he was lying
which is just the first and a couple of really frustrating parts of the story
but now gas had basically been thrown on
the whiteCat witch hunt dumpster fire
and so this would lead
to his two most controversial and hated live plays
the two that I think truly doomed him in the long run
first we'll take a look at his live plan Monster
which looks perfectly fine for the vast majority of its run time
until it reaches the ending
where whiteCat did this
when looking at this
I still always think it's sped up
and I even got so convinced
to the point where I was trying to figure out why he'd speed up
only the end of the video
but it really was just the result of adrenaline
I would say that at this point he was truly doomed
not because none of the previous things
mattered but instead
because this is the point of no return
like now no matter what he did
with a suspicious looking live play
a crazy low play time
and a ban from the main server
there wasn't much he could do
to actually prove that he was legit
but he would do his absolute best
uploading one last live play
the legendary proof i'm legit
if you look at this from an outside perspective
you might think that this is what doomed him
it both got him banned from the private server that he was playing on up to this point
and became one of the most controversial posts
of all time when our slash Osu game
but the comments under it tell a sort of different story
since none of them really say much about
this live play
because it's actually quite good
he did everything they wanted
but what he was met with was a hundred plus comments
about how all his other live plays were hacked
there's a lot to unpack in these comments
so let's get into it
first his keyboard sounds wrong
and he did a stream during a jump section
this is a completely reasonable thing
to be suspicious about
but it also has a really simple explanation
and they actually tap five times at all
the audio is really just him bottoming out his keys
because he's tapping harder during the harder section of the map
which is why it's so annoying
that so many people are harping on this as being
the end-all be-all of evidence against him
and then there are the big one's
the first of these is that his cursor teleports
during his monster live play
and this one is so weak
it's the only one that really hits me is blatantly witch hunty
since if you watch the video slow down
you can see him make the movements
you see on screen exactly and
then move his body forward blocking the pen
so you can't see him move the cursor
to its resting position
the thing is that either of these
likely not have enough to convince people
but there was one more thing
and those were the two seemingly unexplainable
parts of his live plays
which are one at the end of his monster live play
white cat tabbed out of the map without pressing any buttons
and two
on the natsukoI hanabI live play
he tabs out
and another score pops up
this looks really weird
and unlike the others common logic can't explain it
since both of them were actually caused by glitches
we now know this
but you can't really blame people for believing them at the time, right?
well I kind of beg to differ
since for each one of these we have to ask the question
what does this mean
and the implication from people claiming that this
part of the live play was edited
is pretty clear
it's that white cat either edit a different gameplay onto a screen
or running a cheat
that has this as its side effect
the first is ridiculous
unless we assume that white cat is a hollywood level vfx editor
the reflections are perfect the way the screen looks is perfect
everything about it lines up way too well
to have been done by an amateur
and the second one means that he was using a cheat
that no other person had used
or has used since
because this bug has not been shown in
any other cheater's live plays
basically,
what i'm trying to say
is that these are completely empty claims that  don't
prove or disprove anything
somehow I feel like i'm getting a bit of deja vu here
But, despite this
when  people came into this live play
thinking that white cow was cheating
and then saw this quote unquote
evidence against him
it would just become crystal clear to them
that he was not a legit player
and the fallout from his live play
would reflect this reaction
when he was banned off the private server he was playing on
and then basically shunned from any public appearances
this was the true lowest point for him
when the people who believe in his legitimacy
could be counted on like one hand
so after losing everything
his account his credibility
and seemingly his chances of ever coming back
what would he do
with basically nothing left
whiteCat would migrate to qatari
with the help of fire digger
who was one of his last supporters at this time
he'd actually played a lot on a different private server
before this and accumulated about 25 000 play count
he'd improved a lot because of this
of this and one score that represents pretty well
how good he'd gotten
was his fc on shisana no udo with hidden hard rock
which would have been the number one on Bancho
and still the number two to this day
this is from a burst
of motivation right after being banned
but after this he would barely play for the next year
yeah you heard that right
between late 2017 and late 2018
white cat would barely touch the game
with his new account on gatarI only ever reaching 15 000 play count
he clearly lost
a huge amount of motivation because of his ban
one of the biggest questions for me though
was always why
why was he banned not only longer than you would be
for multI accounting or boosting other accounts
but longer than you'd be banned for cheating
by an entire year
and he wasn't not unbanned for a lack of trying
that's for sure
every three months which is the minimum amount of time for an appeal
he would send another unban appeal
meaning that over time he sent him at least 10 separate appeals
and every single one of them was rejected
he was never given a reason why
it just happened
like he'd made multiple live plays
he'd streamed he'd done everything
and yet the player base and Osu! support
seemed to be firmly against him
and this seemed to be what truly made him lose hope
since it would begin
his year-long hiatus
which should only end
in the middle of 2019
when he once again wanted to attempt
being unbanned
this period of about four months
between when he came back and
when he was actually unbanned
is really interesting to me
since I was watching his first stream
and he was a mid to low top 50 player
like he tried firey's difficulty of quaver
with 3 mod
and he got 80% on it
he's now gotten 99 on the map
with the same mods
so what the hell happened
in those four months
whiteCat's return to playing osu
in early 2019
is really interesting for a couple of reasons
first because of how average player
he really was by this point
whereas in 2016 and 17
he distinguished
himself
with top 50 aim
and some of the best Ez,DT players in the game
with those exact same skill sets
and skill levels he'd been passed
by a huge number of players
after just a couple weeks of playing actively though
he would begin to distinguish himself
for his skills, he was strong in DT
and in what was most definitely his best play at the time
he achieved the first ever DT fc
on that weird circle of monochrome butterfly
and also FCed fiery's Guess Who Is Back
But,
but overall none of his dt plays
from early 2019
even cracked 800 pp
and there weren't many exceptional plays
outside a monochrome butterfly
he did also have a lot of really
impressive no mod and hard rock scores though
like the first ever fc on the awaken's diff of Youka to Yumeutsutsu
and the Song's Comp(ilation) FC which was five pp
away from his first 800.
I also don't want to downplay his skill too much
especially because just a few weeks after this
he had scores like a CookiezI snipe
on high score of all things
a couple of things to remember from this time though
are that he couldn't read AR11
not even close
and his aim was good but nothing exceptional
and overall he was generally
pretty rounded
this wouldn't remain the case for long though
because whiteCat had essentially been sitting on
an absurd amount of potential for three years
and it was finally starting to come out
since after becoming acclimated with the game
again he would start trying faster maps
and in late april of 2019 he would show just how good he had the chance to get
when he got the first DT FC on the extra diff Black Rover
yes even before azerite who was top 10 at the time
this was a score Vaxei, rafis and firebat hadn't been able to achieve
and it was his first 800 as well
he would then fc the top diff of Guess who is back
which would have been the first DT FC on Bancho
he would then get his first ever 900 pp play
on fiery's diff of (???) before it was ranked on Bancho
this had already been done by FlyingTuna
but it showed how he kept realizing
more and more of the massive potential he had
but he's still yet
have a true magnum opus
a play that set him apart from everyone else at the time
especially because as his aim
kept getting better it became increasingly
more and more clear
that he'd be able to set something
unmatchable
and this would all come to fruition
when after being active for a couple of months
he'd finally get a truly legendary score
a Milk Crown hidden, hardrock 4 miss
imagine getting less misses with hard rock
than anyone else had on the map
on the map
which was 0.1 stars away from 10 stars
this score is stupid
it's still unmatched to this day
even by WhiteCat himself
if he'd been unbanned at the time
it would have been the score that made people reconsider
what kind of a player he was
like what on earth even is this
this is the moment for me that white cat became so much
more  than the average top 50 or even top 10 player
because while this play didn't technically break any barriers
it's not a stretch at all to say
that it was the best aim play  in the game
when just months after he started playing actively he set something like that
that's when it became crystal clear
just the kind of potential that he had
to realize his potential fully outside of love maps though
white cat would need to work on a few things
high AR
speed and stamina
these were the three things he seemed to struggle the most on
in comparison to other top players
the high hour reading actually wasn't bad at all
but since 3 mod had eventually become such an important part
of how he played
it being in such a weak state
in hindsight was clearly a hindrance
and so his AR looks in practice during this time (???)
would become extremely important
and then there was speed
where he fell far behind
VaxeI Kathy and even idke
who were the ones who was becoming increasingly
clear he'd be competing with
and then in terms of stamina
after not playing for such a long time
it seemed like he'd lost a ton of it
and he struggled a lot with accuracy longer, higher bpm streams
so between June when he came back in September
would he manage to change these things
well yeah
there's a pretty stark difference in his streams
between these two periods
when you look at mid-2019
it's clear that he has a lot going for him
but he's fairly inconsistent and he would sometimes go
multiple streams without any really impressive scores
but by september
he's choking a Wizard's Tower 1000 pp play
then choking the longer version of Monochrome Butterfly
and getting the lowest miss-count up to that point
then 3 missing fiery's Colorful for like 800 pp
and then 1 missing the top diff make a move
which at that point had no FCs
and he would do things without magnitude
just about every stream
but when this difference in skill truly
became clear was in one score
a play that defined him growing into his strengths
and what may have been his best play at the time
his Wizard's Tower 1000 pp play
this changed things
it reclassified him as a player
only two other people had a 1000 pp play at this point
and now someone who's basically unknown
just did it offline
in these few months he took shape
as a player and laid the groundwork
for one of the most memorable events in osu's history
an event which marked a shift in the game's meta
the start of an era
and the redefinition of what it meant to be good at aim
the situation that whiteCat was in
in the days leading up to his unbanned were
peculiar to say the least
on Bancho he would have technically been number three
in terms of pp
and when I asked him what he thought his actual skill level is
at the time he believed number two might be doable
and at the same time as all of this
he was still streaming to basically no one
but there were just a few people who'd stuck with him throughout this time
the three most pivotal being firedigger, Skill and MyAngelAku
the most important one up to this point
had most certainly been firedigger
he was the only one who gave WhiteCat a platform after his banned
twice on other servers
he had also been one of the only people who trusted him since the beginning
this probably should have given him some leverage
for gaining back favor in the community
but sadly just as the whiteCat situation was unfolding
another incident happened
yes I have analyzed it and it's not really that suspicious you can
you can ironize as much as you want but
I'm willing to
to believe that this play is legit
yeah firedigger would give whiteCat and legendary  the same treatment
and since legendary was well less than legit
firedigger really didn't have the ability to change anyone's mind
and this had stayed the case for the last three years
throughout these years MyAngelAku had
also spent a lot of time defending whiteCat
he was like why catch a ride or die
he'd spent the last three years arguing tooth and nail for whiteCat's legitimacy
despite no one believing him
like in legit every whiteCat thread he was there defending him
and then Skill who had known of white cat and tried to
convince others of the legitimacy for years
but had never been super public about it
in these three Skill had something the others didn't
and that was a high profile in the community and long lasting ties with top players
when waikel was originally banned
he was one of the people convinced that he was cheating
but after finding with the number one spot in a couple of private servers he
began advocating for whiteCat's legitimacy
although at that time it was mainly behind closed doors
in August he went public with it though
with a tweet that read
please unban whiteCat it's sad the literal top 5 players in banned
for three years
this would create a bit of a stir, but
a little over a month later
towards the end of september
Skill would tweet out again
with some much more extensive proof
and a request to retweet to spread awareness
it gained a lot of attention very quickly
and with some high profile retweets
it was able to reach peppy himself
and although peppy had to get in one last obnoxious tweet
before it could happen
whiteCat would finally be unbanned
what the f**k is going on in chat
um
"dude um"
you just got f**king unbanned
"What's?"
"You got unbanned!!!"
after 3 years
15 appeals and being banned twice
whiteCat would finally be able to play on Bancho
but before setting his first score
he said
"Okay"
"let's go on to farming guys"
"I don't know if I still have the stamina"
"but i'll try it"
he would then go on to play for four hours
and in the process change the course of the game's history forever
stream started off pretty slow
he struggled a bit on some pretty easy maps
but he picked up pace quickly
FCed fiery's diff on quaver
then Hime Hime and
then literally out of nowhere
in like three attempts
he fc the Union
"rip acc,"
"What the f**k it's"
"YES!!!!!!"
this was the second highest pp play ever at the time
and it got people to understand
that they weren't just dealing with a normal top 10
or even top 5 contender
but someone who could potentially rival VaxeI at the top of the game
he would then follow this score
with a Song's Complication FC and a myriad of 700 pp plays
in a quantity that had never really been seen before this point
it skyrocketed him
in a single day to becoming one of the most popular figures in the community
it's also very clear that at this point
whiteCat is still a developing player
he was still struggling with 3 mod and he didn't even
play any maps over 300 bpm
but despite this he'd reach #109 in just a single day
this absurd show of skill
also gave people a lot of questions
the biggest of which had to be is
whiteCat a DT 1 trick
it was reasonable enough seeing as every
play he set on the 20sec. was with DT
and on the main server
he'd really yet to show any potential on hardrock, nomod
or even reading
finding the answer to these questions
as well as watching someone who seemed to have a top three level of skill
what motivated thousands of people to tune into his stream the next day
where he would once again do things that
no one else besides maybe VaxeI was
he got like five 1000+ combo run on tsukinami in a row
and he even got a two miss run
then in like two tries
he FCed KanI *do Lock for 860 pp
he then 1 missed Wizard's Tower
with 1000 pp acc
he'd follow this with an 890 pp score on Guess Who Is Back
then, 846 pp on Colorful
and then a 3 miss
on the 9.64 star Immortal Flame
which is seven stars without DT
and overall he'd play for two and a half hours
and peek at 6k viewers
becoming one of the biggest players in the game
and reaching #27
2 days later he would once again start his game
and in his best day yet
he would FCed Yume Chizu
becoming the first person after three years
to beat Cookiezi's choke
and then he'd also FC 1HOPE SNIPER
which is a ridiculous 700
and one of the first to be done with nomod
it also seemed like he just couldn't stop
getting seven hundreds
on seemingly every map he played
there were at least eight
in just the three hours he played that day
and because of this he'd reached his biggest milestone yet
entering the top 10.
this is where it should have become hard
the top 10 was on a different level than everyone else
and especially as you approach #1
it started to seem like even WhiteCat have trouble
since the time VaxeI had the biggest pp  lead in the history of the game
the game everyone wanted to see just how close he could get to the top
and with players like VaxeI at the top
who had multiple 1000 pp plays
it seemed like he still had a lot to prove
he himself only believed that it
was possible to reach number two because of this
but this certainty that VaxeI would hold the number one spot
would get put into question the next day
and this can be placed
squarely on one thing
he put on three mods
and then became a farming god
with a KanI *do Lock 3 mod score for
938 pp
fiery's Lonely Go! 3 mod for 904 pp
and even Black Rover extra difficulty 3 mod for 950 app
and his new top play
this would bring him to number seven by the end of the day
and also give him the record for by
far the most 900s ever set in a single day
he would then boot up his stream the next day
just to outdo himself
there's really only one score you need
to understand why this day was so out of the ordinary
Team Magma  3 mod
s rank
"F**k off"
"Holy f**k"
"Holy shit"
this is one of those scores that
no other player could do
that no player could even dream up
no one had passed the map with these mods
and he 3 modded it
he wasn't just good
or even top three material
but in certain categories of play
he was years ahead of everyone else
that day he also got 972 pp on Guess Who Is Back
950 on KanI *do
and 806 in the top diff Back Rover
which was far far outside of everyone else's skill set
he went from number seven to number four
in a single day
a spot which he overall reached  in just five days
he'd boot up his stream a bit later and play in a multi-lobby
but three days later he'd come back
and show everyone just how capable he was the number one spot
getting three separate 900s in a single day
and making it all the way to the number two  spot
which really just left him with one more thing he needed to do
before he truly make it clear that he was worthy in the number one spot
a 1000 pp play
despite everything
whiteCat had still yet to set a 1000 pp play
and while he put in a lot of good attempts and shown that it was
probably possible
it was definitely the one big thing setting apart from Vaxei
and later this stream he'd start putting in attempts
on Lonely Go!
this map really is boiled down
to a 10 second dip spike at the end
and when he first started trying it, it seemed
pretty unlikely
since he was failing there most of the time
and then after that he got mind blocked on the beginning
and overall it looked really bleak
until he got this run
"Holy shit!"
he ended this day at number two
and at this point he was finally approaching the last hurdle
Vaxei's massive unmatched lead in terms of pp
he had two 1k(s) and he'd made it clear that he was in a different caliber
than everyone else playing on Bancho before this point
and he had a variety of skills and plays
that WhiteCat was just not able to compete with
with his accuracy on normal DT maps
being far ahead of whiteCat's
But,
whiteCat had something else of his sleeve
and that was unmatched ability
to gain performance points
"We got it boys!"
whiteCat reached #1 just 14 days after his unbanned
and to say it made waves about the community
would be a massive understatement
he had both gained a huge amount of notoriety
and with this gained a lot of people who
didn't like the attention he was getting
one thing a lot of people really assumed at this point
was that he was a DT1 trick
which was an easy conclusion to come to
seeing as most of his impressive plays
of the time were with DT
but in a lot of people who expressed his opinion
there was also a sense of denial
I would know since the time
I was one of them
and I think this can be most clearly felt
through the comments on an idke clip
where it kid basically said that he thought
WhiteCat's stream was boring because he only farm
he made it pretty clear in the clip that he didn't think this was
all WhiteCat could
but that it was all he was doing at the time
a lot of people didn't seem to get this though
and so some of the comments are pretty naive
and kind of hilarious to look back on
like one guy said it would be cool
if he could set scores like Euphoria or sound Chimera
uh-huh
because unlike icky you could obviously
never do those scores
but this also puts pretty well what else
whiteCat still had to prove
because while obviously he's at the #1 spot now
he'd still yet to show skill in many things besides farming
and since he'd reach #1
he would finally have the chance
to prove this
over the week after he hit #1
whiteCat wouldn't play much
but upon his return on the 10th of October
he would warm up a bit
before putting in some attempts on Team Magma
he'd played the map a fair bit in the weeks prior
after his s rank
which at the time may have been his most impressive score
but seeing as he only had one 1k
it seemed unlikely to get another run with
that kind of luck
since the map would give 1.1 kp if he have seated
he seemed to think differently though
since he'd put in many attempts after
sadly though he'd basically been mind blocking the map since
but after this week break
when he came back to the map
he did this
he set his magnum opus play the time
taking the pp record
getting the first 1.1 k
and doing it all only three weeks after being unbanned
even looking over everything before this point
this score is absurd
it was unmatched by every other player in the game
and completely out of even whiteCat's league
just a couple weeks ago
with this score he cemented himself as having
far and away the best jumping in the game
and while it certainly wasn't proving him
as a diverse player
it did prove to everyone just how unique the player he still was
finally though after this he seemed to be satisfied with
where he was
and he could finally stop farming
which would give him the opportunity to prove
everything else
or the #1 score on Souless 4
and then a 3 miss on Warriors with hidden
before going back to farming for like an hour
and then choking a 10 star fc
he really wasn't doing himself any favors
with how good he was at aim
since those scores had always overshadowed
everything else he did
but as the weeks went by he'd play
more and more outside of aim
and he would prove a ton
and finally by the end of October
he seemed to finally be finding his groove
when he FCed Tengaku
it's definitely an aim map
I don't think it's an overstatement to say
the hardest part was the speed aspect
which certainly set it apart this time from his other scores
and then after this he would choke 1HOPE SNIPER
with hdhr
this play makes no sense
there still wasn't no mod fc outside of his
and on top of this only a few people even passed the map with hidden, hardrock
he just 2 missed it
and then only a week later
he did this
again he is not doing himself any favors
by being this good at aim
especially when he followed this with a milk crown 9 star fc
literally mental
he also pocketed himself 250 dollars so
it was probably worth it as well
also that accuracy
it just doesn't make sense
over time it's easy to get desensitized
when you repeatedly see dominance like this on aim
but he really did get the best act by an entire percent
while seeing one of the most popular aim maps in the entire game
throughout this section i've still mainly been talking aim
but that doesn't mean he wasn't playing a whole lot of stream maps
actually it was the opposite
he was playing a ton of them and he'd gotten way way better
now it is important to note that before this point
whiteCat was not bad at both stream speed and aim
but over this time he'd obviously gotten better at both of those
where this practice really counted though
was in stamina
since before this point well whiteCat wasn't
awful at stamina
and in comparison to people like Vaxei
or especially idke  it was abysmal
and this is where his training had really paid off
since while it still wasn't mind blowing
it gave him the wiggle room to show off his already great flow aim
I think the score that best shows how big of a transformation he'd had
is most certainly his Sound Chimera one
where he managed to get the best accuracy on the leaderboards
of a map that's basically just streams
and this newfound stream skill
led him to set his sights
on one of the most sought after scores in the entire game
a Euphoria FC
nearly every top player had tried with the score
but every single one of them had been stopped by one fact
and that is the euphoria doesn't just need jump or flow aim
but it needs an exceptionally high level of both
because after some pretty easy streams in the beginning
it has a ridiculously difficult jump section
it's 8 star's jumping
and it made it impossible for most stream players
to set the score
but with how simple the streams before this
were most aim players would have probably had a pretty good chance on it
the problem was that the map doesn't just end there
it has a very long stream section at the end
that is by no means ridiculously hard
but also by no means is easy
it goes super space at a couple parts. and
and it even has follow points
and this is why it's sort of perfectly fit in to the player that WhiteCat is becoming
a score to almost prove his well-roundedness
and that's exactly what he did
the second highest no mod pp play
and one that had been sought after by a huge number of players
and even grinded by idke
and yet WhiteCat would be the first fc
hitting not only the 280 bpm jumps
but also the extremely space streams at the end
around this time
I and a lot of other people still sort of
thought of WhiteCat as a DT 1 trick
but this score changed things
he wasn't just good at streams
he was exceptional of them
and there was basically no way to deny anymore
just how good he was
to this day the score is still mind-blowing
since everyone on the leaderboards has more than 5 misses
so where do you go from here
after setting most of the best aim plays in the game
both in terms of jump and now even some flow aim
what do you do next
well if you're white cat you just keep getting better
WhiteCat would keep the stamina grind up
while also pulling off some pretty nice aim scores
his stream practice meant that 210 and even 220 were now completely inside of his comfort zone
and this combined with his aim
gave him scores like (???)
which no other stream players had managed to pull off
it was pretty clear that in terms of streaming
he was now more than proficient
and he was going to be able to set some pretty impressive scores
despite this anticipation though
no one could have possibly expected him
to pull off one of the most impressive flow aim scores of all time
while also breaking one of the longest curses in osu history
but that's just what he did
WhiteCat can FC Road of Resistance with hard rock
he ended a three year long curse
and concluded it in the most satisfying way possible
with literal god tier accuracy that was one percent above the second best in the map
he wasn't just able to play streams anymore
instead he was at the forefront of them
but despite this ridiculous show of skill
there was one thing he was still lacking in
220 bpm plus stamina
he was able to stream it
it but instead of the god tier act he could get on
anything below that bpm
he struggled much much more
with both the aiming and tapping parts and maps like YomI Yori
one other thing that he decided to double down on during this time
was diversifying his aim
since while in terms of comfortable aim it was nearly unmatched
when it came to less comfortable aim
it was just not quite on the same level
but before he started out grinding on these skill sets
he went back and did just a little farming
it's honestly comical just how little he has to try
he was not playing the same game as everyone else
switching from ridiculous play to
ridiculous play every time he streamed
and while during the bulk of 2020
he'd still play a lot of 3 mods aim
would also diversify a huge amount of the maps he played
and by the middle of the year he'd set
three 1kpp plays
all on three mod farm maps
but more significantly
he got scores like a tool assisted speed chord hidden hard rock 30 miss
the first DT A rank on Airman
an EmbryO hard rock fc for 800 pp
a Song's Compilation FC for 800 pp
and a dive bomb hidden hard rock score
are just a few plays that showed him
in a very very different layer
all throughout he was also getting much
better at higher bpm stamina
reading and aim control
which would cause these months to seem a whole lot slower
but it would pay off
big time
since he'd reached the point where 220 was
almost completely inside of his comfort zone
and I think his thought process probably went something like
what's the most legendary 220 bpm map
and that's how he set his sights on a YomI YorI score
but at the same time
YomI YorI was one of the most played maps in the entire game
and white cat had really just picked up 220 stamina
so it seemed unlikely they'd go and like set the number one score or something right, well
this score is absurd
he picked up 220 and then
did this somehow
it showed a ridiculous amount of skill and talent
and it's basically the perfect score
to show the player that he was becoming
someone not just proficient in
comfortable aim
ut instead someone had built on this aim skill
to enable him to do scores that
no one else could even fathom
oh by the way he also got 1.1 k
and his new top play on the new anime band
and a 3 mod fc on the newly ranked imagination
for nearly the same amount
just WhiteCat things, right
I also think it's really interesting when you see how quickly he improved
after his unbanned to think about something else
like a lot of people talk about what would have happened if someone like Mathi
kept playing during the time that he quit because of community pressure
but what about white cat if he never got banned
like because of his ban
he legitimately didn't play during the most formative years for him as a player
now with the ridiculous amount of catching up he did after his unban
I feel like it's clear the potential he had
was and kind of still is
the most the game has ever seen
and especially when we've seen mrekk
come to his own the way he has over the last couple months
it really makes you think
since white cat really did start out
improving just as fast
okay tangent over
point is that after his unbanned
WhiteCat had seemed to become an entirely different player
when there was not only skill to jumping
but now a much wider range of aim
on top of also being very skilled at stamina
and at this point there were really two major things that he needed to do
to keep improving
at what he was already doing
and prepare for the Osu! World Cup
l would essentially be his first tournament performance
as the months went on a lot changed
for one his aim got a whole lot better
which can be entirely summed up
by one ridiculous score
the best aim play in the game
and one of the best snipes ever
what a funny guy
sniping the previous best aim play in the game
with what a lot of people considered to be the best
other scorers he would get would include
a Galaxy Collapse 6 miss
which was only the best in the map by 50.
also an s rank on fiery's 9* Happppy Song
happy song getting the best miscount by six
and choking 1.1 k pp with nomod
he would also continue to reap the benefits
of his now extremely solid stamina
with, you know
a YomI Yori fc for 960 pp
oh and remember when I said that it wasn't clear if
uncomfortable aim was really a strong suit
well he'd do this
this is basically also equivalent to that
guy who solved integrals for eight hours
like the aim control and just aim in general required for this map
are ridiculous
and I just want to remind you that just a couple months before this
people were saying that it'd be cool if he could play anything outside of 3 mod
this time in mid 2020
would end up marking WhiteCat's peak
in terms of pure domination of his skill sets
it was a time when there was no question about who the best aim player in the game was
and many even began to compare his seemingly massive reach
and absurd amount of unique plays to Cookiezi
he had the largest pp gap in history
and he held it without even trying
it's no exaggeration to say that he was the face of the game
and the biggest celebrity had seen
since Cookiezi
this is all amazing
but the word peak is important here
since this point would mark the start of a break for WhiteCat
and somewhat the end of the WhiteCat's era
after his mid-year pop off
white cat would definitely slow down a fair bit
well except for you know
Goodbye Moonmen happening
just casually setting the second highest
star non-cheesed fc
at only 0.6 stars away from a 10 star fc
but after this he'd
play very little for the next couple of months
which would cause him to lose a lot of his speed and stamina
which seemed pretty worrying in the lead up to the world cup
but importantly his aim was
definitely still there
like for god's sake
he got the first 10 star FCed during this time
still this point would mark a massive slowdown in whitecat scores
and it also came right before he was going to get the chance
to prove the final thing he hadn't had the chance to
after his unbanned, his tournament performance
in the biggest osu event of the year
in the Osu! World Cup
he hadn't been able to participate in any tournaments
before this point
because after you're unbanned
you have to wait a year before you can play in a single one
and so
while only playing a couple
official tournaments before his ban
WhiteCat was about to play his first
one
since his unban
in the biggest
tournament of the year
before it started there were a lot of
rumors
about his tournament skill
since
while he'd proved to be fairly versatile and aim
in many skill sets he hadn't
shown much  of anything
like there wasn't
anything saying that he wasn't
good at
low ar hidden reading
but he also didn't
have any scores
that showed that he was
this meant everything sort of
came down
to this one event
but with his first
tournament being the biggest tournament
of the year
it also raised a lot of
questions
since he'd never been in a
tournament
of this caliber before was he
gonna get super nervous
and fall apart
and what does aim even hold up in a
tournament setting
but still when it was
revealed that he'd be
part of the german
team
people got really excited
especially because of how the german
team had been
gaining momentum over the
last few years
and white cat just seemed
to be the cherry on top
since they'd
hovered near the top
in 2018 and 19
but had been just shy of the top both
times
and they already had a pretty
insane roster
with a Dustice
who had always been the
standout player on the team
as one of
the best tournament players in the game
and someone who got even stronger on the
harder pools
Okinamo, a space stream god
Umbre, i don't know if you've heard of Umbre
he's kind of good at getting
accuracy on streams
and finally hallowatcher
a very good all-around player who was
especially good at hidden, hardrock
but this team had a problem
in that
while all of them were great
and dustus
was consistently a contender
for one of
the best players in the tournament
many of them had still yet
to come fully
into their own
but in 2020
umbre had done this thing
okinawa had gone from a space stream god
to being one of the most skilled speed
players
in the entire tournament on top
of that
and now they got the number one player
in the game
who if nothing else should be able to
prop up their roster in a huge way into
later pools
as the maps get harder as
the tournament goes on
this was where he was predicted to
really shine
since it's where many
players technical ability becomes their
ceiling
this was where germany had failed before
and so WhiteCat gave him a critical piece
to play
on top of this
the German team gained
(???)
who was an extremely strong in aim
and high AR asset(???)
which filled another
hole from their 2019 team
and this stacked roster
got a lot of
people thinking
and hoping
that maybe
for the first time in two years
they might actually be able to give the U.S.  a run for their mind
like in the
last year when they got fourth
it was
really quite good
but in the top two spots
there was a
critical difference
in that one team was able to 7-0 a team
that had already beaten germany by a
decent amount
it was a legitimately boring match to
watch
since there really wasn't a competition
if you were betting on a U.S. match
the
biggest question would be if the other
team
could even score a single point
they didn't just have four players that
could outcompete everyone
no they had the undisputed two best
turnout players in the game
along with
probably the majority of the top ten
it wasn't even funny
while people certainly had high hopes
for the german team
saying they would
beat the U.S.
was still a bit far-fetched
so with all this in mind
the world cup
began
germany would place fourth in the
qualifiers
with a performance that
wasn't bad
but one that also in no way
proved them
to be a very special team
the U.S., Canada, and Poland would all
outperform them
meaning they had a lot
to prove in their
matches
Germany's first match was
against the 29th seed turkey
and it went
about as expected
Germany going
to be winning this match five
to zero
five zero will never not be a great
score
but at the same time it doesn't
prove that much
Germany's second match was against the
20th seed indonesia
and this one was a
roller coaster
germany would start off by getting a
3-1
lead over indonesia
which seemed like it
would end in a pretty expected 5-1
victory
but Indonesia would then proceed
to win the next three matches
giving
them the lead
and bringing them to
within one point of defeating Germany
luckily with a couple of pretty great performances germany was able to take the win
but this match really didn't
inspire confidence
it seemed like people
had way overestimated the team's ability
and sadly it seemed like WhiteCat's
ability
to change the team was at the
center of that
because while he played
quite well
he certainly hadn't
revolutionized the team
or even seemed
to make much of a difference at all
Germany would have their first match
against one of the top teams
when in the quarterfinals they would play South Korea
the previous year's second place
finishers
and this year's fifth seed
south korea started the tournament
looking quite shaky
but in their last
match it pulled it together pretty well
which meant that germany was gonna have
to play much
much better to even stand a
chance against them
and that they most certainly did
they were looking way better this
match
and WhiteCat and Okinamo start standing
out a lot more
and this match made it
especially clear what germany was going
to be strong on
and what they weren't
going to be
since when it came to jumping and flow aim
they were very very strong
with WhiteCat Dustice and Onion
all being some of
the best aim players in the tournament
and on top of this with Okinamo on their team
along with WhiteCat and Dustice
they had a team that were ridiculously
strong on speed
but when it came to a
lot of the hidden and alternating picks
south korea was clearly much much
stronger
but despite this
Germany was
able to win one of South Korea's picks
while not losing any of theirs
and take
a 6-4 win
after just scraping by with the last two
matches
Germany would come face to face
with the United States